In this video we'll define something
called the cost function. This will let us
在这段视频中我们将定义代价函数的概念 这有助于我们
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
figure out how to fit the best possible
straight line to our data. In linear
弄清楚如何把最有可能的直线与我们的数据相拟合
regression we have a training set like
that shown here. Remember our notation M
在线性回归中我们有一个像这样的训练集 记住
was the number of training examples. So
maybe M=47. And the form of the
M代表了训练样本的数量  所以 比如 M = 47
hypothesis, which we use to make
predictions, is this linear function. To
而我们的假设函数 也就是用来进行预测的函数 是这样的线性函数形式
introduce a little bit more terminology,
these theta zero and theta one, right,
接下来我们会引入一些术语 这些θ0和θ1
these theta i's are what I call the
parameters of the model. What we're
这些θi我把它们称为模型参数 在这个视频中
going to do in this video is talk about
how to go about choosing these two
我们要做的就是谈谈如何选择这两个参数值θ0和θ1
parameter values, theta zero and theta
one. With different choices of parameters
选择不同的参数θ0和θ1
theta zero and theta one we get different
hypotheses, different hypothesis
我们会得到不同的假设 不同的假设函数
functions. I know some of you will
probably be already familiar with what I'm
我知道你们中的有些人可能已经知道我在这张幻灯片上要讲的
going to do on this slide, but just to
review here are a few examples. If theta
但我们还是用这几个例子来复习回顾一下
zero is 1.5 and theta one is 0, then
the hypothesis function will look like
如果θ0是1.5 θ1是0 那么假设函数会看起来是这样
this. Right, because your hypothesis
function will be h( x) equals 1.5 plus
是吧 因为你的假设函数是h(x)=1.5+0*x
0 times x which is this constant value
function, this is flat at 1.5. If
是这样一个常数函数 恒等于1.5
theta zero equals 0 and theta one
equals 0.5, then the hypothesis will look
如果θ0=0并且θ1=0.5 那么假设会看起来像这样
like this. And it should pass through this
point (2, 1), says you now have h(x) or
它会通过点(2,1) 这样你又得到了h(x)
really some htheta(x) but
sometimes I'll just omit theta for
或者hθ(x) 但是有时我们为了简洁会省略θ
brevity. So, h(x) will be equal to just
0.5 times x which looks like that. And
因此 h(x)将等于0.5倍的x 就像这样
finally if theta zero equals 1 and theta
one equals 0.5 then we end up with the
最后 如果θ0=1并且θ1=0.5 我们最后得到的假设会看起来像这样
hypothesis that looks like this. Let's
see, it should pass through the (2, 2)
让我们来看看 它应该通过点(2,2)
point like so. And this is my new h(x)
or my new htheta(x). All right? Well
这是我的新的h(x)或者写作hθ(x) 对吧？
you remember that this is
htheta(x) but as a shorthand
你还记得之前我们提到过hθ(x)的 但作为简写 我们通常只把它写作h(x)
sometimes I just write this as h(x). In
linear regression we have a training set,
在线性回归中 我们有一个训练集
like maybe the one I've plotted here. What
we want to do is come up with values for
可能就像我在这里绘制的 我们要做的就是
the parameters theta zero and theta one.
So that the straight line we get out
得出θ0 θ1这两个参数的值 来让假设函数表示的直线
of this corresponds to a straight line
that somehow fits the data well. Like
尽量地与这些数据点很好的拟合
maybe that line over there. So how do we
come up with values theta zero, theta one
也许就像这里的这条线一样 那么我们如何得出θ0 θ1的值
that corresponds to a good fit to the
data? The idea is we're going to choose
来使它很好地拟合数据的呢？我们的想法是 我们要选择
our parameters theta zero, theta one so
that h(x), meaning the value we predict
能使h(x) 也就是 输入x时我们预测的值
on input x, that this at least close to
the values y for the examples in our
最接近该样本对应的y值的参数θ0 θ1
training set, for our training examples.
So, in our training set we're given a
所以 在我们的训练集中我们会得到一定数量的样本
number of examples where we know x decides
the house and we know the actual price of
我们知道x表示卖出哪所房子 并且知道这所房子的实际价格
what it's sold for. So let's try to
choose values for the parameters so that
所以 我们要尽量选择参数值 使得
at least in the training set, given the
x's in the training set, we make
在训练集中 给出训练集中的x值
reasonably accurate predictions for the y
values. Let's formalize this. So linear
我们能合理准确地预测y的值
regression, what we're going to do is that I'm
going to want to solve a minimization
让我们给出标准的定义 在线性回归中 我们要解决的是一个最小化问题
problem. So I'm going to write minimize over theta
zero, theta one. And, I want this to be
所以我要写出关于θ0 θ1的最小化 而且
small, right, I want the difference
between h(x) and y to be small. And one
我希望这个式子极其小 是吧 我想要h(x)和y之间的差异要小
thing I'm gonna do is try to minimize the
square difference between the output of
我要做的事情是尽量减少假设的输出与房子真实价格
the hypothesis and the actual price of the
house. Okay? So let's fill in some
之间的差的平方 明白吗？接下来我会详细的阐述
details. Remember that I was using the
notation (x(i), y(i)) to represent the
别忘了 我用符号( x(i),y(i) )代表第i个样本
ith training example. So what I
want really is to sum over my training
所以我想要做的是对所有训练样本进行一个求和
set. Sum from i equals 1 to M of
the square difference between
对i=1到i=M的样本 将对假设进行预测得到的结果
this is the prediction of my hypothesis
when it is input the size of house number
此时的输入是第i号房子的面积 对吧
i, right, minus the actual price that
house number i will sell for and I want to
将第i号对应的预测结果 减去第i号房子的实际价格 所得的差的平方相加得到总和
minimize the sum of my training set sum
from i equals 1 through M of the
而我希望尽量减小这个值
difference of this squared error,
square difference between the predicted
也就是预测值和实际值的差的平方误差和 或者说预测价格和
price of the house and the price
that it will actually sell for. And just
实际卖出价格的差的平方
remind you of your notation M here was
the, the size of my training set, right,
我说了这里的m指的是训练集的样本容量
so the M there is my number of training
examples. Right? That hash sign is the
对吧
abbreviation for "number" of training
examples. Okay? And to make some of our,
这个井号是训练样本“个数”的缩写 对吧 而为了让表达式的数学意义
make the math a little bit easier, I'm
going to actually look at, you know, 1
变得容易理解一点 我们实际上考虑的是
over M times that. So we're going to try
to minimize my average error, which we're
这个数的1/m 因此我们要尝试尽量减少我们的平均误差
going to minimize one by 2M.
Putting the 2, the constant one half, in
也就是尽量减少其1/2m 通常是这个数的一半
front it just makes some of the math a
little easier. So minimizing one half of
前面的这些只是为了使数学更直白一点 因此对这个求和值的二分之一求最小值
something, right, should give you the same
values of the parameters theta zero, theta
应该得出相同的θ0值和相同的θ1值来
one as minimizing that function. And just
make sure this, this, this equation is
请大家一定弄清楚这个道理
clear, right? This expression in here,
htheta(x), this is my, this is
没问题吧？在这里hθ(x)的这种表达 这是我们的假设
our usual, right? That's equal to this
plus theta one x(i). And, this notation,
它等于θ0加上θ1与x(i)的乘积 而这个表达
minimize over theta zero and theta one,
this means find me the values of theta
表示关于θ0和θ1的最小化过程 这意味着我们要找到θ0和θ1
zero and theta one that causes this
expression to be minimized. And this
的值来使这个表达式的值最小
expression depends on theta zero and theta
one. Okay? So just to recap, we're posing
这个表达式因θ0和θ1的变化而变化对吧？
this problem as find me the values of
theta zero and theta one so that the
因此 简单地说 我们正在把这个问题变成 找到能使
average already one over two M times the
sum of square errors between my
我的训练集中预测值和真实值的差的平方的和
predictions on the training set minus the
actual values of the houses on the
的1/2M最小的θ0和θ1的值
training set is minimized. So this is
going to be my overall objective function
因此 这将是我的线性回归的整体目标函数
for linear regression. And just to, you
know rewrite this out a little bit more
为了使它更明确一点 我们要改写这个函数
cleanly what I'm going to do by convention
is we usually define a cost function.
按照惯例 我要定义一个代价函数
Which is going to be exactly this. That
formula that I have up here. And what I
正如屏幕中所示 这里的这个公式
want to do is minimize over theta zero and
theta one my function J of theta zero
我们想要做的就是关于θ0和θ1 对函数J(θ0,θ1)求最小值
comma theta one. Just write this
out, this is my cost function. So, this
这就是我的代价函数
cost function is also called the squared
error function or sometimes called the
代价函数也被称作平方误差函数 有时也被称为
square error cost function and it turns
out that Why, why do we, you know, take
平方误差代价函数 事实上 我们之所以要求出
the squares of the errors? It turns out
that the squared error cost function is a
误差的平方和 是因为误差平方代价函数
reasonable choice and will work well for
most problems, for most regression
对于大多数问题 特别是回归问题 都是一个合理的选择
problems. There are other cost functions
that will work pretty well, but the squared
还有其他的代价函数也能很好地发挥作用
error cost function is probably the most
commonly used one for regression problems.
但是平方误差代价函数可能是解决回归问题最常用的手段了
Later in this class we'll also talk about alternative
cost functions as well, but this, this
在后续课程中 我们还会谈论其他的代价函数
choice that we just had, should be a
pret-, pretty reasonable thing to try for
但我们刚刚讲的选择是对于大多数线性回归问题非常合理的
most linear regression problems. Okay. So
that's the cost function. So far we've
好吧 所以这是代价函数 到目前为止 我们已经
just seen a mathematical definition of you
know this cost function and in case this
介绍了代价函数的数学定义
function J of theta zero theta one in case
this function seems a little bit abstract
也许这个函数J(θ0,θ1)有点抽象
and you still don't have a good sense of
what its doing in the next video, in the
可能你仍然不知道它的内涵
next couple videos we're actually going to
go a little bit deeper into what the cost
在接下来的几个视频里 我们要更进一步解释
function J is doing and try to give you
better intuition about what its computing
代价函数J的工作原理 并尝试更直观地解释它在计算什么
and why we want to use it.
以及我们使用它的目的
【果壳教育无边界字幕组】翻译：antis  校对：cheerzzh 审核：所罗门捷列夫